<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;तिरुवेङ्कटाचार्य-प्रस्तावः on काव्ये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;तिरुवेङ्कटाचार्य-प्रस्तावः on काव्ये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Historical value</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/historical-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/historical-value/</guid>
      <description>It is an irony that the country with the most ancient civilization should have very few original histories about its past. Strictly speaking, the only historical work of the past worth the name of history is Kalhana&amp;rsquo;s Rājatarangini, which tells the story of the kings of Kashmir. Bana&amp;rsquo;s Harshacaritam is no doubt very valuable as a biography but there is a great deal in it that does not partake of the nature of correct history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madurai conquest</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/madurai-conquest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/madurai-conquest/</guid>
      <description>1. THE POLITICAL CONDITION PRECEDING THE CONQUEST Among the territories that suffered the worst rapine and plunder was Ma&amp;rsquo;bar. According to Khusrau’ Ma’bar lay within that distance from Delhi which could be reached after a normal journey of twelve months. As Khusrau says, the Muslim arrows had never reached that distant land”. As regards the identity of ĪMa’bar there is no doubt. The region of the Coromandal east of Peninsular India might be said to correspond roughly to what was known to Arab geographers as Ma&amp;rsquo;bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/preface/</guid>
      <description>The Madhurāvijayam or Vīra Kamparāya caritam by Gangā Dēvi was discovered by accident amidst a heap of worn out palm-leaf manuscripts as part of a series of Sanskrit works; and, but for the careful scrutiny of the Head Pandit of the curator of Sanskrit Mss. Trivandrum, it would have gone the way of many other works of the past which are not available to us. The original is in grantha characters and is full of errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAMBUVARĀYAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/sAmbuvarAyas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/sAmbuvarAyas/</guid>
      <description>II. THE SAMBUVARĀYAS
1. VĪRA CHAMPA The Madhurāvijayam, as its title signifies, is the story of the conquest of Madhurai by Kumāra Kampaņa told by his wife Gangā Dēvi. But the poem treats also of the factors which formed the prelude to the Madhurai conquest. The way to Madhurai lay through the Tondai mandalam which was at that time ruled by the Sambuva rāyas. It is not certain whether the Sambuvarāya kings were on friendly terms with the new kingdom of Vijayanagar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The poet</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/poet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/poet/</guid>
      <description>The peculiar interest of this biographical poem is that its author Gangā Dēvi was the wife of the hero whom it celebrates, and that in all probability she accompanied her husband in his sojourns in the South. She was the chief queen of Kampaņa II, and though nothing is known about her lineage, must have sprung from a noble family as the Dēvi suffix would imply. She was very highly accomplished and was endowed with all charms and grace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viajayanagara invasions of Tondaimandalam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/vijayanagara-invasions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/00_tiruvenkaTAchAri/vijayanagara-invasions/</guid>
      <description>IV. VIJAYANAGAR INVASIONS OF TONDAIMANDALAM
1. THE SAVANNA INTERREGNUM It is believed by some scholars that it was Venrumankondān I the Sambuvarāya ruler (1322 1339) who was overcome by Kampana. But this view is far from correct as the earliest inscription of Kampana bears only the date 1352.2 His invasion of Tondai mandalam could never have taken place prior to that year. Venrumaņkondān had a peaceful death and the period was also calm and quiet in his territory, and this is borne out by the fact that his son Kājanārāyana was able to send the remains of his royal father to be consigned to the Ganges.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
