<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>सङ्गीतम् on काव्ये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in सङ्गीतम् on काव्ये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recorder</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/recorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/recorder/</guid>
      <description> Tongue before ntoes  Lessons  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AuOMLRWJtDc#t=206.16925  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>अलङ्कारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/alankAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/alankAraH/</guid>
      <description>आवलिः  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>तालम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/tAlam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/tAlam/</guid>
      <description>Western beats Clef notation   Notation of duration   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>परम्पराः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/paramparAH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/paramparAH/</guid>
      <description>कर्णाटकसङ्गीतम् कर्णाटकत्वम् शास्त्रकृतः  Among the Kannada speaking musicologists who wrote in Samskṛta, we should include Vidyāraṇya (Saṅgīta Sāra), Kallinātha (Saṅgīta kalānidhi, a commentary to Śārṅgadēva’s Saṅgīta Ratnākara), Rāmāmātya (Svaramēḷa Kalānidhi), Paṇḍarīka viṭhala (Sadrāga Candrōdaya, Nartana Nirṇaya) Gōvinda Dīkṣita (Saṅgīta Sudhā ), Veṅkaṭamakhi (Caturdaṇḍi Prakāśikā) and Muddu Veṅkaṭamakhi (Rāgalakṣaṇa). We can not forget that even though Śārṅgadēva’s forefathers came from Kashmira, he lived and wrote his work Saṅgīta Ratnākara in the courts of Yadava Singhana, a Kannada speaking king who ruled from Devagiri.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>रागः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/rAgaH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/rAgaH/</guid>
      <description>देशनामानि  Three regions are prominently seen in raga names -Karnāṭa (Karnataka), Baṅgāḷa/Gauḍa (Bengal) and Gurjara/Saurāṣṭra (Gujarat). So we find raga names such as Gurjari, Saurāṣṭra, Suraṭi, Baṅgāḷa, Śud’dha baṅgāḷa, kannaḍa, Sindhu kannaḍa, Kannaḍa gauḷa, Kannaḍa baṅgāḷa, Māruva kannaḍa etc. While it is impossible to say why or how these names have come to use, it is a good guess that such ragas became popular in those regions and then spread to other parts of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>साहित्यम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/sAhityam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/sAhityam/</guid>
      <description>विभागः पदः  a specific type of composition with a pallavi, an anupallavi and several charanas. The pallavi line is repeated after the anupallavi and each of the charanas.  History  The earliest Haridāsa from Karnataka is Narahari tīrtha from the 14th century and there are two padas attributed to him. So it is very likely the type of composition pada originated in Kannada too. Later on, during the 15th century, more padas were composed both in Kannada and Telugu by Śrīpādarāya and Annamayya respectively who were contemporaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>स्वरः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/svaraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/shAstram/sangItam/svaraH/</guid>
      <description>आवलिः  सामवेदे उपस्वराः  प्रयङ्कम् विनतम् नमनम् अभिगीतम् सम्प्रसारणम्  Western notation  “b” stands for flat and “#” stands for sharp. Flat means to play the note a half step lower, while sharp means to play the note a half step higher.  Clef notes   Clef Diagram   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
