<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;आङ्ग्लानुवादः on काव्ये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;आङ्ग्लानुवादः on काव्ये विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/1/</guid>
      <description>Slökās 1 to 16: Gangā Dēvī&amp;rsquo;s obeisance to the poets who influenced her.
 May the elephant-faced God, who, like the divine Kalpavrksa fulfils ihe desires of those that sur render to His Grace, be propitious to the good. For the sake of wisdom, I prayerfully approach God Śiva and His Spouse, who embody the light of Universal Consciousness and who bear the form of the Creator&amp;rsquo;s model for making man and woman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/2/</guid>
      <description>Slökäs 1 to 13: Queen Devāyi conceives. Her longings during pregnancy are described.
 The queen conceived by the king and bore in her womb, the seed of royal race, as the cosmic waters held in them the tējas virile of Brahma with which the three worlds were created. The queen put aside her jewels. Her face was somewhat pale like the sara reed and her form unusually slender. She shone like a river in autumn with lotuses gone and with the globe of the moon reflected on its watery surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/3/</guid>
      <description>Shlokas 1 to 20: The early training of Kampana. His bodily charm and qualities are also described. His marriage with Gangū Dēvī and other princesses is mentioned.
 The tonsure ceremony over, the prince be came proficient in all the arts and humanities without any external help, and tuition by gurus in his case was more or less a superfluity. He was trained in military science by his own father who had acquired its secret from an excellent master.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/4/</guid>
      <description>Shlokas 1 to 16: Preparations for the march on the Sam buvarāya territory.
1 &amp;amp; 2. When the divine sun, the sustainer of lotuses, and the unequalled lamp of universe, rose the next day, the prince woke up from his sleep, and after duly performing the morning rites of worship, ordered his generals to get the army ready for marching. 3. Then, like the noise of the ocean, churned with the mountain of Mandhara, the sound of war-drums beaten by drum-sticks arose at the beginning of the march.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/5/</guid>
      <description>Shlokas 1 to 11: Kampana installed himself Governor of his father at Marakatanagara (Kanci) and established good government.
 Then in the great city called Marataka which was like an ornament of this earth, king Kampaņa established himself and ruled the earth peacefully and well. His subjects thought that he was another incarnation of Vişnu that had come down to this earth, . because he was so victorious, and such a favourite of gods and virtuous men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/6/</guid>
      <description>Shlokas 1 to 69: The water-sports of the Prince.
 Like Indra always attended by celestial nymphs, the king with his ladies moved to his pleasure garden which resembled Nandana, to gather flowers. The ladies followed the king as he began to move to the garden, with their jewelled girdles sound ing. The sight of it was like a line of humming bees moving in the wake of the southern gale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/7/</guid>
      <description>Shlokas 1 to 50: Day and Night described. Gangā Dēvi&amp;rsquo;s description of Night to her husband.
  Then the sun, as if afraid of the offence he had given to the queens by making lotuses imitate the beauty of their faces, sunk into the caverns of the western mountains.
  From there he submerged into the waters of the Western Ocean as if to replenish his heat from the submarine fire there-heat which had been spent in the day in making lotuses blossom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kAvyam/TIkA/padyam/madhurA-vijayam/AnglAnuvAdaH/8/</guid>
      <description>Shlokas 1 to 20: The final battle with the Muslims.
 Bow-men severed the hands of elephant riders with Ardhachandra arrows; and they fell down in the pool of blood in the battle field like serpents in the sacrificial fire of Parikshit&amp;rsquo;s son.
son Pearls from the broken heads of elephants in rut attacked by heroic warriors, fell down blood-tinged like sparks produced in sudden collision. No sooner did a horseman begin to return after having cut with his sword the frontal globe of an elephant than that elephant was seen seizing his horse between his legs and squeezing him.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
